<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'
      xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'
      xml:base='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/ongoing.atom'
      xml:lang='en-us'>
 <title>ongoing by Tim Bray</title>
 <link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/</id>
 <link href='./' />
 <link rel='self' href='' />
 <link rel='replies'       thr:count='101'       href='/home/tbray.org/www/html/ongoing/comments.atom' />
 <logo>rsslogo.jpg</logo>
 <icon>/favicon.ico</icon>
 <updated>2011-08-01T13:48:24-07:00</updated>
 <author><name>Tim Bray</name></author>
 <subtitle>ongoing fragmented essay by Tim Bray</subtitle>
 <rights>All content written by Tim Bray and photos by Tim Bray Copyright Tim Bray, some rights reserved, see /ongoing/misc/Copyright</rights>
 <generator uri='/misc/Colophon'>Generated from XML source code using Perl, Expat, Emacs, Mysql, Ruby, Java, and ImageMagick.  Industrial-strength technology, baby.</generator>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/31/'>
 <title>Still Life Paintings of Daisies</title>
 <link href='Still-Life-Paintings-of-Daisies' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='0'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Still-Life-Paintings-of-Daisies#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/31/Still-Life-Paintings-of-Daisies</id>
 <published>2011-07-31T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-31T22:58:28-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>One of my favorite online activities is the discussion of photography and (often very loosely) related subjects over at  <a href='http://pdml.net'>PDML</a>.  A thread last March made me want to take pictures of daisies to serve as examples to support a point I was trying to make on the subject of nothing less than Art Itself.  Unfortunately, this far north (and with a cool spring) they&#x2019;ve been hard to come by.  But I found some.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>One of my favorite online activities is the discussion of photography and
(often very loosely) related subjects over at 
<a href="http://pdml.net">PDML</a>.  A thread last March made me want
to take pictures of daisies to serve as examples to support a point I was
trying to make on the subject of nothing less
than Art Itself.  Unfortunately, this far north (and with a cool spring)
they’ve been hard to come by.  But I found some.</p>
<img src="RUNE2415.png" alt="Daisies" />
<p>I’d posted some other shots of flowers, acknowledging that they were
steeped in cliché.  This provoked a polite storm of only moderately-cynical
argument, in which one gentleman offered “I think about the retirement home
with little old ladies taking oil paint lessons so that they can do still life
paintings of daisies.”  Since then I’ve been hell-bent on making a still-life
of some daisies.</p>
<img src="RUNE2419.png" alt="Daisies" />
<p>This probably isn’t it, since the subjects of Still Lives are often
inanimate not to mention dead, and these here daisies were swaying
briskly in the wind and drinking in the sun.  But still, I’ve been hunting these little
suckers for months, so here they are.</p>
<img src="RUNE2421.png" alt="Daisies" />
<p>Now I have to remember what it was I was trying to say about Art.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/31/'>
 <title>Good News-Biz News</title>
 <link href='Talking-Points-Memo' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Talking-Points-Memo#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/31/Talking-Points-Memo</id>
 <published>2011-07-31T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-31T10:20:31-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business/Publishing' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Publishing' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Politics' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Politics' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>People still read news, but the howls of pain from the  business grow always louder; the news about the news is all layoffs and paywalls.  I&#x2019;d like to offer a cheery counter-example.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>People still read news, but the howls of pain from the 
business grow always louder; the news about the news is all layoffs
and paywalls.  I’d like to offer a cheery counter-example.</p>
<p>Let’s start with a boring corporate press release:
<a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/tpm-ad-sales-revenue-up-88-in.php">TPM
Ad Sales Revenue Up 88% In First Half of 2011</a>.  “TPM” 
stands for
<a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/">Talking Points Memo</a>.  I’m a fan.
Like most people who find politics and policy interesting, I’ve enjoyed the
last few years of US politics.  In particular I’ve been 
watching America’s self-induced “debt-ceiling” meltdown with a sick
fascination.
And like most people with interesting jobs, I don’t have that
much time to invest in being a politics junkie.</p>
<p>So, what I do is read TPM.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Back Story</h2>
<p>TPM started as the personal blogging vehicle of
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josh_Marshall">Josh Marshall</a>; I
followed a link from somewhere to the blog back in 2003 or so and was pretty
well instantly hooked.</p>
<p>So were a lot of other people, and several times a year on TPM there are
stories about how they’re opening a new office or hiring a new reporter or
whatever.</p>
<p>Also, within a few weeks of my starting at Google, I noticed on
<a href="http://twitter.com/joshtpm">Josh Marshall’s tweetstream</a> that they
were having severe pain with an upgrade in their Google ads machinery.  I
managed to get lucky and find the right Googler to tell, and the story had a
reasonably happy ending.  But along the way, I learned the realities
about the kind of dollars a successful site like TPM can pull in, and let me
tell you, they’re eye-opening.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Conclusion</h2>
<p>It’s obvious: Right now in the twenty-first century, it’s perfectly
possible to run a healthy, profitable, growing business built entirely on news
and opinion.  Thus, the incumbents who are shrinking and screaming and cutting
and charging must, in some respect, be doing it wrong.</p>
<p>The reasons why TPM has succeeded seem straightforward; let me try to
capture a few:</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>Voice</h2>
<p>TPM’s is strong and personal. Originally it was just
Marshall’s, but he has brought other voices to the fore who, while broadly
consistent with his, are clear and distinct.</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>Writing</h2>
<p>It’s good; polished, well-proofread, nearly 100% free of grammar and usage
glitches.  And at the same time, lighthearted, colloquial, transparent.</p>
<h2 id='p-8'>Reporting</h2>
<p>I’ve read a lot of different sources on this subject matter, and I think
TPM offers the best reporting you can get.
They tell the story, in a way that’s free of cant and
jargon, of what the dynamics are in any of Washington’s debates; who matters,
which issues are the sticking points, and what’s likely to happen.</p>
<p>They find out first, then they dive deeper.  That’s what reporting’s
supposed to be.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Passion</h2>
<p>There is a school of thought out there holding that all politicians are
thieves, wastrels, and fools; so hopelessly corrupt that “don’t bother voting;
it just encourages them”.</p>
<p>Which is bullshit.  Politicians are <em>people</em>
and sure enough, some are corrupt or foolish or just mean.  But a high
proportion really do think that government is something that is not only
necessary but a good place to invest effort with the goal of improving
the world.  And the ones I’ve known have been, by and large, pretty smart.</p>
<p>TPM is appropriately (and amusingly) cynical about
misbehaving politicoes (check out the hilarious
<a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/news/2010/12/your_nominees_for_the_2010_golden_duke_awards.php">Golden
Duke Awards</a>).  But it’s obvious at every moment that they really do
believe in politics as a grand civic process; that what happens in
Washington is real and matters; and that on most of the big issues, some of
the proposed paths are better and some are worse.</p>
<h2 id='p-7'>Transparency</h2>
<p>TPM is not neutral; its viewpoint is mainstream-US-liberal,
which is to say they’re right-wing by world standards, and baby-eating commies
in Republican eyes.</p>
<p>They are remorseless in their attacks on Republican illogic, stupidity, and
duplicity.  But they are also pretty ruthless with misbehaving Democrats, both
on matters of policy and (increasingly, of late) tactics.</p>
<p>They are 100% transparent in their biases, and I’m certain many Republican insiders,
who disagree profoundly, still read TPM because they value the quality of the
reporting and analysis.</p>
<p>There may be one or two Republican readers out there, and to them I’m
sorry, but in the Dubya-and-since era, treating that party as substantially
either crazy or 
stupid is a fairly mainstream position.  Possibly the Republicans are
right that homosexuality weakens marriage and tax cuts don’t cause deficits
and imprisoning a world-leading proportion of your population increases public
safety and deregulating the finance industry is good economics and invading
large Middle-Eastern nations (then staying) improves America’s security, as does spending
more on the military than the rest of the world put together. And
maybe the 
rest of the world is wrong on these things.  I doubt it, though.</p>
<p>But I digress.</p>
<h2 id='p-9'>The Good News</h2>
<p>We need the news business to keep us informed and manage democracy
in a sane way.  Here we have an existence proof that the business, run
correctly, is still a good one to be in.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/27/'>
 <title>Suggestions and Additions</title>
 <link href='Suggestions' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Suggestions#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/27/Suggestions</id>
 <published>2011-07-27T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-27T22:28:39-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Life Online' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Life Online' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>These are the ways that you circle people on <a href='https://plus.google.com'>Google+</a>.   The streams of names, most with little photos but some naked, burn time but I can&#x2019;t stop.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>These are the ways that you circle people on
<a href="https://plus.google.com">Google+</a>.  
The streams of names, most
with little photos but some naked, burn time but I can’t stop.</p>
<ol>
<li><p>The word “friend” groans under an overload of meaning.</p></li>
<li><p>There are so many names that I think I should know but probably I really
don’t, they’re just names that sound like you should know them.</p></li>
<li><p>Some people have funny names.  We all know the controversy about G+ and
Real Names, but some of the funny names are really Real.</p>
<p>Sometimes the humor
is a tribal thing; to an English speaker, names from the Balkans and
parts of Africa are most inclined to be humorous.
I wonder if having a
funny name changes your life?</p></li>
<li><p>I have a short attention span; have never held a job for a
decade. I’m sad, watching names go by of
people who were colleagues, realizing in so many cases that there’s
little connection left.</p>
<p>I should hang on tighter to people.</p></li>
<li><p>There’s a real pleasure in dismissing suggestions for people you
despise.  
Sometimes they come back and you can reject them again!</p></li>
<li><p>Sometimes a name pops up and you’ll smile because they’re good
people you haven’t thought of recently.</p></li>
<li><p>Putting a name in circle is a Secret Activity. 
I wonder how well you have to get to know someone before they “Show you
their circles”?</p></li>
</ol>
<p>After I typed this, I checked those lists and found the names of
<a href="https://plus.google.com/104869833877339397479">Ken Gardner</a>, 
<a href="https://plus.google.com/105703208184646222757">Jarrad Blackshear</a>, 
<a href="https://plus.google.com/101505889021595741586">主役ちゃん</a>,
<a href="https://plus.google.com/105770711929721820826">Caron Levy</a>,
<a href="https://plus.google.com/108704215810307213851">Bor Fekon</a>, 
<a href="https://plus.google.com/110112795725092334951">Ed Giblett</a>, 
<a href="https://plus.google.com/114899845560334637612">Jon Bosak</a>,
<a href="https://plus.google.com/109301427702438627230">Ricardo Acuña</a>, and 
<a href="https://plus.google.com/107429251778993111827">Jilliana Natalie</a>.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/21/'>
 <title>Japanese Brazilian Market</title>
 <link href='Liberdade-Market' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Liberdade-Market#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/21/Liberdade-Market</id>
 <published>2011-07-21T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-21T23:30:41-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Brazil' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>S&#xe3;o Paulo claims to have the largest &#x201c;Japantown&#x201d; in the world; it&#x2019;s called <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liberdade'>Liberdade</a>.  Herewith three photos of items on sale there.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>São Paulo claims to have the largest “Japantown” in the world; it’s called
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liberdade">Liberdade</a>.  Herewith
three photos of items on sale there.</p>
<img src="RUNE2056.png" alt="On sale in Liberdade, São Paulo" />
<p>It’s a big city; claims to be the largest, with fifteen million souls or
more,
in both the Western and Southern hemispheres. It’s not scenic or glamorous or
touristic or fashionable, mostly; it’s about people focusing on working their
way into the First World.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Liberdade</h2>
<p>It’s jam-packed and cheery and culturally variegated to a
ridiculous extreme; worth walking around.  This visitor from the other
hemisphere and perimeter of the New World felt at home; I’m used to a crowd
where the faces represent every possible permutation of the gene pool.  On the
other hand I’m also used to a cheery cacaphony of languages; but São Paulo is
almost as unilingually Portuguese as Tokyo is Japanese.</p>
<img src="RUNE2064.png" alt="On sale in Liberdade, São Paulo" />
<p>Anyone who’s studied a South-European language will be able to make out
quite a bit of Portuguese text, but the vowels and consonants might as well
come from Timbuktu or Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<img src="RUNE2065.png" alt="On sale in Liberdade, São Paulo" />
<p>Our Brazilian host Bruno, a Google colleague with whom I’ve spent
considerable time, showed me some sort of official document and I saw that
his middle name was Takahashi.  A fresh glance at his face and I realized I’d
been blinded by name and accent; he wouldn’t draw a second glance on a Tokyo
subway car. We see through our minds not our eyes.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/18/'>
 <title>Piracy</title>
 <link href='Piracy' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='12'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Piracy#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/18/Piracy</id>
 <published>2011-07-18T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-18T22:20:41-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business/Mobile' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Mobile' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I&#x2019;d like to draw your attention to <a href='http://blog.gameized.com/2011/07/12/the-huge-success-of-an-appstore-failure/'>The huge success of an AppStore failure</a> by Lu&#xed;s Fonseca of <a href='http://gameized.com/'>GAMEized</a>. It&#x2019;s the sad story of a mobile-game developer running into the reality that there&#x2019;s a lot of pirated software out there. I think the obvious conclusions are wrong, mostly.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I’d like to draw your attention to
<a href="http://blog.gameized.com/2011/07/12/the-huge-success-of-an-appstore-failure/">The
huge success of an AppStore failure</a> by Luís Fonseca of
<a href="http://gameized.com/">GAMEized</a>.
It’s the sad story of a mobile-game developer running into the reality that
there’s a lot of pirated software out there.
I think the obvious conclusions are wrong, mostly.</p>
<p>(GAMEized had perhaps the worst possible outcome, observing piracy rates on
the order of 90%.  They got unlucky, having been prominently
featured on one of the biggest steal-apps-here sites.)</p>
<p>Let me start by saying that this isn’t an Apple-specific problem; there are
pirates on the Android side, too.  It’s not even a mobile-apps problem,
<i>per se</i>, but a monetizing-bags-of-bits problem.</p>
<p>Countermeasures are the conventional response:  Keep the pirates from
getting their hands on the bits, stop ’em getting the warez to
their customers, and prevent the customers from using these ill-gotten goods.
What GAMEized in their blog calls “functional counter-piracy safeguards”.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>What I Don’t Believe</h2>
<p>Let me call out two quotes from that 
post:</p>
<blockquote><p><i>It’s reasonable to assume that many if not most of the
16,000 users playing FingerKicks on Apple’s Game Center probably wouldn’t be
playing a pirated version if it weren’t so readily available</i></p>
<p><i>The game’s popularity was skyrocketing but the losses from piracy were
mounting</i></p> 
</blockquote>
<p>The first quote sort of makes sense: if you could stop piracy, fewer people
would play pirated games.  But consider the second, in particular the phrase “losses
from piracy”.  It presupposes that there was a ton of potential revenue out
there that GAMEized would have taken home, but for the pirates.</p>
<p>Why on earth would anyone believe that?  This postulates that there are
a significant number of people who <em>could</em> pay for software if they
wanted to, <em>would</em> have paid $0.99 for this game, and thus
GAMEized lost that money.</p>
<p>I don’t buy it.  The pirates’ customers are people who go to the
trouble of signing up 
with flagrantly-illegal warez sites, either because they’re penniless
teenagers or just sleazy; people whose time is worth so little they’re
willing to skulk around the dark side to save a buck.  Once again, let me
borrow words from the blog: “people who willingly crack existing apps just to
save — or steal — 99¢”.  Well, yeah; and you seriously think that you’re going
to make money on one-time sales of bags-of-bits to this flavor of pond scum?
On what planet?</p>
<p>Fortunately, the planet contains huge numbers of people who <em>will</em>
cough up a buck for a nifty-looking app.  Enough to have taken this market
from zero to billions since 2007.  There’s business out there for
smart, creative people.  But let’s draw the right lessons.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Choose Your Business Model</h2>
<p>I’m still convinced that free downloads followed up by in-app revenue
is an immensely better approach than a one-time charge for
access to a bag of bits.</p>
<p>Yes, the <i>banditos</i> can sometimes hack the in-app buying
transaction, but it’s a <em>lot</em> more work so the economics are against
them.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Competing With “Free”</h2>
<p>Apple, with the iTunes store and its successors, proved that 
you can do this; “easy and convenient” can win.</p>
<p>So maybe the single
best thing the app retailers can do is to make the buying experience
increasingly quick, lightweight, friction-free, and delightfully
entertaining.  After all, most people like to shop sometimes.</p>
<p>It’s still worthwhile for the Apple and Android communities to
whack the pirate moles whenever our hammers have a target in reach.</p>
<p>But still, the best antipiracy tactic isn’t a negative countermeasure,
it’s being proactively and positively delightful.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/17/'>
 <title>Tisa</title>
 <link href='Tisa' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='13'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Tisa#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/17/Tisa</id>
 <published>2011-07-17T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-17T23:04:31-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Web' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Web' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Publishing' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Publishing' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>A couple of days ago <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/15/Gone-Neuton'>I switched</a> the <a href='http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Neuton'>Neuton</a> typeface into this space, via <a href='http://www.google.com/webfonts/#ChoosePlace:select'>Google Web Fonts</a>.  I liked it but a lot of others didn&#x2019;t, and it turned out that for some reason, on Windows it just didn&#x2019;t work as a body font; I suspect it&#x2019;d be fine for display purposes (as in, for headlines).  So, on to Plan B: <a href='http://typekit.com/fonts/ff-tisa-web-pro'>FF Tisa Web Pro</a>, from <a href='http://typekit.com/'>Typekit</a>.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>A couple of days ago
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/15/Gone-Neuton">I switched</a> the
<a href="http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Neuton">Neuton</a> typeface
into this space, via
<a href="http://www.google.com/webfonts/#ChoosePlace:select">Google Web
Fonts</a>.  I liked it but a lot of others didn’t, and it turned out that for
some reason, on Windows it just didn’t work as a body font; I suspect it’d be fine for
display purposes (as in, for headlines).  So, on to Plan B:
<a href="http://typekit.com/fonts/ff-tisa-web-pro">FF Tisa Web Pro</a>, from
<a href="http://typekit.com/">Typekit</a>.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Why Tisa?</h2>
<p>I spent a really excessive amount of time trying this font and that, but
at the end of the day the choice was easy.  I wanted something that was really
easy to read, unobtrusive, and yet struck my eye as “modern”, whatever that
means.</p>
<p>I was also struck by the narrative: “Mitja Miklavčič drew FF Tisa to meet
the technological and aesthetic requirements of modern magazine use.” Because,
all these years into the blog experience, I now think that’s what this wants to
be: a modern magazine.  This has become clearer with the rise of Twitter
and Tumblr pushing the limits of the short form, and then of Facebook and
Google+, working on publishing-as-conversation.</p>
<p>Also, I’m prone to italics, and some otherwise-great fonts
tend to crumble when bent over. That’s a big problem with Georgia,
which has otherwise served me pretty well here all these years.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Mechanics</h2>
<p>Setting up Typekit fonts is not quite as much of a no-brainer as are Google
Web Fonts.  Their “Kit Editor” Web application is nicely-designed but
accumulates entropy and has to be relaunched every so often.</p>
<p>The real pain-in-the-butt is caching.  The font download for Tisa (I left
out the bold-italic variant) is 110K; so yes, please cache it.
Except for when I’m twiddling CSS
selectors, or trying to A/B back and forth between a couple of fonts.  For Safari
in particular, if you want to un-cache a font, you have to take the ship up
and nuke the site from orbit; <i>it’s the only way to be sure</i>.</p>
<p>What I eventually did for A/B testing was to set up three copies
of the same page, and hand-edit them to put <code>class="F1"</code> on each
paragraph tag in the first, <code>class="F2"</code> in the second, and so on.
Then I set up a Typekit kit including all three fonts with <code>.F1</code>,
<code>.F2</code>, and <code>.F3</code> selectors.  Kind of gross, but it got
me there; there’s just no substitute for looking at the options
side-by-side.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Finance</h2>
<p>I signed up for Typekit’s “Portfolio” package at $49.99/year. This strikes
me as a fair price for what they offer, and I have no urge to “own” a font.
If Typekit becomes unreasonable down the road, I’m sure there will be lots of
competitive options.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/10/'>
 <title>Women&#x2019;s World Cup Quarterfinals</title>
 <link href='Womens-World-Cup' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Womens-World-Cup#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/10/Womens-World-Cup</id>
 <published>2011-07-10T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-15T17:19:12-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports/Soccer' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Sports' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Soccer' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I hadn&#x2019;t planned it, but am having a slow single-parent weekend and tuned in by accident. I was hooked in the first 30 seconds and watched three of the four.  I probably won&#x2019;t be able to take in any more, but I&#x2019;d unhesitatingly recommend that you do if you can.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I hadn’t planned it, but am having a slow single-parent weekend and
tuned in by accident. I was hooked in the first 30 seconds and watched three of
the four.  I probably won’t be
able to take in any more, but I’d unhesitatingly recommend that you do if you
can.</p>
<p>Compared to the men’s event, it lacks some power and pace; but
there’s no shortage of elegance or precision or passion or courage or
desperation.  My heart was in my throat over and over.</p>
<p>There’s less of the childish cowardly diving and related
sleaze that taints the men’s version; but it’s not entirely on the up-and-up.
In particular the Brazilian women need to un-learn some of the lessons they’ve
absorbed from those other players with Y chromosomes.</p>
<p>One thing the women’s game does have is a small but noticeable contingent
in warpaint; I’m talking makeup, and not just a little bit either.  It’s
interesting that some wear it but others don’t.  I can’t, as a mainstream straight
man, claim that I look at women the same way I do at men, and that’s just
fine.
The faces that touched my heart were mostly without warpaint; but not entirely.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>France over England, on penalties</h2>
<p>Fair result.  The English were gallant but the French were deeper and
better conditioned.  It really shouldn’t have needed the penalties,
particularly since England was hardly there in the overtime.  Both of the
regular-time goals were brilliant, particularly Jill Scott’s opener.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Germany 0 Japan 1</h2>
<p>I started watching this match neutral but the Japanese women won my
heart with their extreme courage against the heavily-favored (not to mention larger)
hosts.</p>
<p>Maruyama’s extra-time goal combined raw speed and neurosurgical finesse.  I
don’t see any of the postgame write-ups bowing in the direction of Japan’s
back line and keeper Kaihori Ayumi; which is stupid, because you don’t take home
a 1-0 win against Germany without something special there.  Kaihori was quiet but I
thought magical.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>USA over Brazil, on penalties</h2>
<p>OMG. This game had more drama than the last two or three rounds’ worth of
games in the last men’s World Cup.</p>
<p>I went in mildly pro-Brazil because they were the underdogs and after all I
spent last week there.  But, like the German audience, I was more and more in
the US camp the further the game went on.</p>
<p>A few points:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>The US opener was technically an own-goal, which is irrelevant.
That cross in from the left was totally lethal; put the ball in at that angle
and pace ten times and you’ll score five of them, doesn’t matter who it went
off.</p></li>
<li><p>I’m not sure if the ref’s call on the repeated penalty shot was right
or wrong, but I respectfully disagree with Jason Snell’s take in
<a href="http://americanmccarver.com/post/7465221334">There’s Always Hope</a>
on the excellent new <cite>American McCarver</cite>.  Marta was going to score
and was dragged down and the right outcome was a red card and Brazilian goal.</p></li>
<li><p>If FIFA doesn’t like people like Snell instantly assuming corruption on
every vaguely-shady play, they should stop being so lame and corrupt.</p></li>
<li><p>Brazil’s Marta is a story that writes itself. She runs faster and
shoots better than anyone else in women’s football and it’s not close;
that second goal was pure voodoo. But on the pitch
she’s a nasty piece of work; I thought the whistles and boos she was getting
from the German stands were well-earned.  Still, it’s a pity that she won’t
be playing in the semis and final.</p></li>
<li><p>That Rapinoe-Wambach nuclear strike in the dying seconds. Wow... things like
that are why live sports is about the only thing I turn on the TV for.
Nobody could ever dream of scripting it.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Anyhow, the better team on the day won, and yep, Hope Solo is a
superstar, warpaint or not.</p>
<p>I probably can’t spare the time off Wednesday for the semis, and hope to be
on an island next weekend, so that’s about it for me and the Women’s World
Cup.  But I want to thank them all for giving so much of themselves this
weekend; I was enthralled.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/15/'>
 <title>Somewhat Dutch-inspired</title>
 <link href='Gone-Neuton' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='15'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Gone-Neuton#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/15/Gone-Neuton</id>
 <published>2011-07-15T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-15T12:00:00-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Web' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Web' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Publishing' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Publishing' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>The full quote reads &#x201c;Neuton is a clean, dark, somewhat Dutch-inspired serif font which reminds you a little of Times.&#x201d;  I just now stripped the old serif/sans choice out of my blog (less marginalia!) and dropped in <a href='http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Neuton'>Neuton</a> for all the body text.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>The full quote reads “Neuton is a clean, dark, somewhat Dutch-inspired
serif font which reminds you a little of Times.”  I just now stripped the old
serif/sans choice out of my blog (less marginalia!) and dropped in
<a href="http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Neuton">Neuton</a> for all
the body text.</p>
<p><i>[Update: Neuton, we hardly knew ye. It’s gonzo,
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/17/Tisa">replaced by FF Tisa Web Pro</a>.]</i></p>
<p><i>[Update: I have verified that Neuton has horribly-malformed lower-case
t’s on Windows, both XP and Win7, both IE and Firefox.  Blecch.]</i></p>
<p><i>[Update: There was a horrible editing error that caused severe breakage in
the HTML header. I have no idea how it ever worked. Fixed, I think.]</i></p>
<p>Using a
<a href="http://www.google.com/webfonts/">Google web font</a> is just as
simple as they claim.  I haven’t noticed a slowdown in the page load but I haven’t
tested yet on a slow network.</p>
<p>This follows some weeks of
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_theory#Paradox_of_choice">paradox-of-choice</a>
paralysis; there are just too many typefaces there that tickle my eye.  So I
sucked it up and pulled the trigger.  I can always change my mind later.</p>
<p>I have two next-steps in mind.  First, to find another pretty face for the
headers.  Second, to go poke around
<a href="http://typekit.com/">Typekit</a>, drop a few bucks, and adopt one of
the high-gloss classics.</p>
<p>I had been rendering the body text in Georgia at 0.95em.  Neuton really
didn’t seem happy at anything less than a full 1.0em, which required a bunch
of irritating little adjustments to margins and line-heights all over the page.</p>
<p>In conclusion: First of all, thanks and goodbye to
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Georgia_(typeface)">Georgia</a>, which
has served me well for years and remains a damn fine all-purpose Web serif
choice.
Second, thanks to
<a href="https://profiles.google.com/artistenator/posts">Brian Zick</a> for
Neuton.</p>
<p>And finally, all this is mostly irrelevant, since almost everyone
who reads this blog is, like you, reading it in whatever some feed reader
thinks will make it look good, not the way I set it up.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/08/'>
 <title>Porto Alegre &#x2014; Usina do Gas&#xf4;metro</title>
 <link href='Porto-Alegre-Usino-Gasometro' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='2'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Porto-Alegre-Usino-Gasometro#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/08/Porto-Alegre-Usino-Gasometro</id>
 <published>2011-07-08T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-08T19:47:41-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>This is a power-generating plant on the waterfront that has been converted for art-and-culture purposes; there&#x2019;s a cinema, a caf&#xe9;, a children&#x2019;s space, and lots of nice walls for hanging pictures.  We got there as dusk was beginning to fall; a treat for the eyes and camera.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>This is a power-generating plant on the waterfront that has been
converted for art-and-culture purposes; there’s a cinema, a café, a children’s
space, and lots of nice walls for hanging pictures.  We got there as dusk was
beginning to fall; a treat for the eyes and camera.</p>
<p>Geeks will agree that there’s a vaguely Aperture-Science feel to the place
(for the rest, that’s a videogame allusion).  These three shots are just me
admiring the space.</p>
<img src="RUNE1930.png" alt="The interior of Porto Alegre’s Usina do Gasômetro" />
<img src="RUNE1962.png" alt="The interior of Porto Alegre’s Usina do Gasômetro" />
<img src="RUNE1972.png" alt="The interior of Porto Alegre’s Usina do Gasômetro" />
<p>There were at least three art presentations; this is from <cite>gravetos
armados</cite>, an installation by
<a href="http://antonioaugustobueno.blogspot.com/">Antônio Augusto Bueno</a> that really reached
out to me. I had actually picked this one to show
before I noticed the shape in the shadows.</p>
<img src="RUNE1941.png" alt="From “gravetos armados” by Antônio Augusto Bueno" />
<p>Here are a couple of eye-candy morsels; shadows and shapes.</p>
<img src="RUNE1936.png" alt="Shadowed portaled wall at Porto Alegre’s Usina do Gasômetro" />
<img src="RUNE1994.png" alt="Intersecting shadowed beams at Porto Alegre’s Usina do Gasômetro" />
<p>The citizens of Porto Alegre should be proud of this space, it’s a fine
thing.</p>
<img src="RUNE1985.png" alt="Blue window on shadowed wall at Porto Alegre’s Usina do Gasômetro" />
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/08/'>
 <title>Porto Alegre&#x2019;s Central Market</title>
 <link href='Porto-Alegre-Market' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='0'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Porto-Alegre-Market#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/08/Porto-Alegre-Market</id>
 <published>2011-07-08T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-08T14:27:56-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Like the rest of town, it lacks the extremes of drama and beauty that conventionally attract tourists. We went there on Wikipedia&#x2019;s recommendation and I&#x2019;m glad, since I got that you&#x2019;re-a-<em>long</em>-way-away-from-home shiver too rarely enjoyed by over-frequent travelers, but always by those who find their photographs rather than planning them.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Like the rest of town, it lacks the extremes of drama and beauty that
conventionally attract tourists. We went there on Wikipedia’s recommendation
and I’m glad, since I got that you’re-a-<em>long</em>-way-away-from-home
shiver too rarely enjoyed by over-frequent travelers, but always by those who
find their photographs rather than planning them.</p>
<p>Boy, was it ever packed on a Friday afternoon.</p>
<img src="RUNE1893.png" alt="Central market at Porto Alegre" />
<p>It’s mostly about raw materials for food and drink.  This being Brazil,
“drink” includes
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mate_(beverage)">mate</a>, and here are some of your options for making it; I
enjoyed the polished hand-lettering.  I have so far failed to appreciate mate,
but I think I’m in a majority; most people (not just Brazilians) seem to like it.</p>
<img src="RUNE1889.png" alt="Tea leaves for  maté at Porto Alegre central market" />
<p>This isn’t the only picture where I had to squeeze between strangers to get
any sort of view of the goods on offer.</p>
<p>There was bric-a-brac as well as food.</p>
<img src="RUNE1907.png" alt="Bric-a-brac for sale at Porto Alegre central market" />
<p>Over at Google+ I ran a
<a href="https://plus.google.com/107606703558161507946/posts/BPgAQrHrphy">picture of an antique-camera stand</a>, worth a glance if you
care about such things.</p>
<p>But really, it was mostly food.  This gentleman had enough English to
tell me that the cod on offer was Norwegian. <em>The best in the world!</em> he
claimed.</p>
<img src="RUNE1891.png" alt="Cod for sale at Porto Alegre central market" />
<p>Elsewhere in the market was a smallish low-roofed L-shaped alley
where all the stalls sold fish; the fishmongers thumped their countertops and
cried their wares with cheery intensity.  But the pictures didn’t come out.</p>
<p>Some of the food was appetizing in essence and presentation.</p>
<img src="RUNE1902.png" alt="Butcher stand at Porto Alegre central market" />
<p>Then there was this.</p>
<img src="RUNE1913.png" alt="Pigs’ heads for sale at Porto Alegre central market" />
<p>I tweeted about this one, remarking “The birds are no longer angry.”  Some
wag tweeted back: “No, they’re around the corner in the poultry section.”</p>
<p>If you’re in town, it’s worth a visit.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/06/'>
 <title>Porto Alegre &#x2014; Around Town</title>
 <link href='Porto-Alegre-1' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='1'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Porto-Alegre-1#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/06/Porto-Alegre-1</id>
 <published>2011-07-06T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-06T19:50:11-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>It&#x2019;s not the most glamorous or glittery place in the world, but it&#x2019;s nice and friendly.  For one reason or another I took a whole lot of pictures in <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Porto_Alegre'>Porto Alegre</a>.  I think I&#x2019;ll have to break them up across a few entries here.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>It’s not the most glamorous or glittery place in the world, but it’s nice
and friendly.  For one
reason or another I took a whole lot of pictures in
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Porto_Alegre">Porto Alegre</a>.  I think
I’ll have to break them up across a few entries here.</p>
<p>It’s a waterfront town, but the water’s fresh, where a bunch of rivers come
together and bunch up enough to be
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gua%C3%ADba_Lake">called a lake</a>.  I noticed a few
nice-looking cottages on islands, and it works just as well as the ocean for
hosting sunsets.</p>
<img src="RUNE1862.png" alt="Sunset from Porto Alegre over the Rio Guaíba" />
<p>There are a whole lot of places to eat, and the food we got was pretty good.
I particularly enjoyed this one; the band jammed into the corner
pumping out the Brazilian beats while the waiters swarmed the floor with
Brazilian beers.  The beats, which were melodious and hot, pleased me more
than the beers, which were bland.</p>
<img src="RUNE1869.png" alt="An upscale sandwich joint with bear and beats in Porto Alegre" />
<p>Over on Google Plus I published
<a href="https://plus.google.com/107606703558161507946/posts/fb6ZAa3Vid6">another picture of the band</a> with a couple dancing.</p>
<p>The food at this joint was upscale sandwiches, really big but surprisingly
light and airy; I didn’t walk away feeling over-stuffed.</p>
<p>I mentioned that the town isn’t strong on glamor and glitter; in fact, it’s
kind of beat-up looking.  This didn’t bother me because it made for
interesting pictures.  Here we have some graffiti that I liked.</p>
<img src="RUNE1878.png" alt="Graffiti in Porto Alegre" />
<p>And here the central market (I’ll have some pictures from inside in
another post) with a really interesting (I thought)
background.</p>
<img src="RUNE1883.png" alt="Central Market in Porto Alegre with elderly buildings behind" />
<p>One evening the sponsors of FISL put on a big <cite>Churrasco</cite> meal.
This is the “Brazilian-style” barbecue that’s penetrated the
world, where the waiters circulate with chunks of meat on swords and you eat as
much as you want.  This meal was accompanied by a song-and-dance performance,
and I’ll leave you with a picture from that.</p>
<img src="RUNE2006.png" alt="Brazilian traditional dancer at Porto Alegre" />
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/06/'>
 <title>FISL12</title>
 <link href='FISL' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='2'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='FISL#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/06/FISL</id>
 <published>2011-07-06T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-06T07:38:59-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Brazil' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I&#x2019;m not sure what the F and I stand for, but the last two letters are for &#x201c;Software Livre&#x201d;; <a href='http://softwarelivre.org/fisl12'>FISL</a> is the largest <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open_source_software'>FLOSS</a> event in the Southern Hemisphere, and brought me to <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Porto_Alegre'>Porto Alegre</a> for a few days.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I’m not sure what the F and I stand for, but the last two letters are for
“Software Livre”;
<a href="http://softwarelivre.org/fisl12">FISL</a> is the largest
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open_source_software">FLOSS</a>
event in the Southern Hemisphere, and brought me to
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Porto_Alegre">Porto Alegre</a> for a few
days.</p>
<p>The crowd is young (a lot of students) and serious.  You’d think setting up
a Tux-cart would be fun.</p>
<img src="RUNE1855.png" alt="Setting up a Tux-cart at FISL" />
<p>Along with all the talks, which are pretty similar in content to what you’d
find at a FLOSS event anywhere, there’s a trade show, which I found kind of
baffling.  Big Oracle booth... huh?  Various organs of government... well, OK,
I guess.  Little Web shops of one flavor or another, sure enough.  But where I
come from, free-software organizations don’t have gleaming glass booths, and
GNU/Linux distros don’t use Russian politicians in their marketing.</p>
<img src="RUNE1849.png" alt="Glossy glass free-software booth at FISL" />
<img src="RUNE1852.png" alt="Alt Linux advertises their use by Putin and Medvedev" />
<p>There was some cool geek fun.</p>
<img src="RUNE1857.png" alt="Technology with sparkly lights at FISL" />
<p>And the speakers were, obviously enough, my very own tribe.</p>
<img src="RUNE1859.png" alt="In the speakers’ room at FISL" />
<p>The people who’ve been pulling this together (for 12 years now!) should be
proud of themselves.  It’s so nice to mingle with herds of geeks who are doing
the thing for its own sake.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/05/'>
 <title>Road Music</title>
 <link href='Traveling-Music' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='13'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Traveling-Music#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/05/Traveling-Music</id>
 <published>2011-07-05T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-05T21:05:09-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Audio' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Audio' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I spend quite a bit of time in hotel rooms.  This is how I arrange my musical backdrop.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I spend quite a bit of time in hotel rooms.  This is how I arrange my
musical backdrop.</p>
<p>I’m sure this is painfully obvious to most of you, but there are a couple
of new-ish technologies involved, and it can be a real quality-of-life
improver, so here goes anyhow.</p>
<p>First of all, you need to go buy a wire like this.  I forget what it’s
called at the nearest big box, but it’s cheap; there’s a small modern headphone jack at each end.  Six
feet (2m) or so seems about right.</p>
<img src="RUNE2072.png" alt="Audio connection cable" />
<p>Next, you need to have a lot of music available.  Since I now have eleven
thousand songs in the
<a href="http://music.google.com/music/">Google Music Beta</a>, and usually
there’s one way or another to manage Internet, I’m set.  But a
normal MP3 player’s worth of tunes will do.</p>
<p>Finally, you need to poke around behind the TV and clock radio in the hotel
room to find an audio jack.  This is where the recipe most often breaks
down, because you need at least one such device in the room.  Every such
product built in the last couple of years has one, but obviously there are
rooms without the necessary.
My average isn’t
100%, but it’s better than half.</p>
<p>These devices will have smallish non-audiophile speakers, but they are
guaranteed to be better than those on whatever mobile device is hosting (or
streaming) your music.</p>
<p>That’s all folks; plug A into B, figure out how to switch the music box’s
input, and tune out the traffic or neighbor or hallway or elevator noise.
Sweet dreams.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2011/07/04/'>
 <title>Things About Google+</title>
 <link href='Google-plus' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='21'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Google-plus#comments' />
 <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2011/07/04/Google-plus</id>
 <published>2011-07-04T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2011-07-04T20:14:39-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Life Online' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Life Online' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Publishing' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Publishing' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business/Google' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Google' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>No, I haven&#x2019;t figured it out.  Neither has the rest of the world.  Which means that now is a good time to write about it, while our impressions remain plastic.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>No, I haven’t figured it out.  Neither has the rest of the world.  Which
means that now is a good time to write about it, while our impressions remain
plastic.</p>
<ol>
<li><p><b>Famous people</b>: The “Suggestions” list kept including them, and I
kept adding them reflexively, because I follow some of them on Twitter.  Then
I stopped, because I follow some of them on Twitter.  I particularly enjoyed declining
the opportunity to add Jason Calacanis.</p></li>
<li><p><b>Pictures</b>: I publish the ones I really care about here on the
blog.  “Really care about” means thinking a bit and some time in
Lightroom color-correcting, cropping, and so on.  I don’t see any reason to
change that part; I want stuff that I care about on my own piece of the
Internet, not anybody else’s, even my employer’s.</p>
<p>But for lightweight picture sharing, where I want to attach some words and
maybe bring a smile to a few faces, G+ seems just the ticket.  Consider
<a href="https://plus.google.com/107606703558161507946/posts/j2CnP6whtBk">The
birds are no longer angry</a>.</p></li>
<li><p><b>Apologies are in order</b>:
There were people, both outsiders and insiders, who went on
the record with statements about how “Google will never get social” or how the
G+ approach was totally stupid.  <em>Eat them words.</em>
I’m not brave enough to predict how the G+ story is going to play
out, but it’s an outstanding piece of design and engineering work; I tip my
hat to the team.</p></li>
<li><p><b>Circles</b>: So far, I’ve mostly posted to the world, but I think
I’m doing it wrong.  I have this blog and Twitter for broadcasting purposes.
So I’ve cooked up a few circles and I’ll make a point of trying to cut the
“Public” posts to maybe just the picture sharing, and route the rest to one
circle or another.</p></li>
<li><p><b>Math math math</b>: I’d rather not join the parade of people
shouting for one new feature or another, because it seems to me that G+ as it
stands hits a decent
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2004/01/14/TPSM-8020">80/20 point</a>.  Having said that, Circles
are, mathematically speaking,
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Set_(mathematics)">sets</a>, and I think
set arithmetic would come in real handy: “Post this to the intersection of my
Photogeeks circle and my Vancouver circle”.  I can think of lots of other
amusing permutations.  The reason I bring this up is because I smile, envisioning a
future in which math teachers use social-network constructs to explain Set
Theory.</p></li>
<li><p><b>At-Work+</b>: Would a sandboxed internal version of something like G+ be useful where
you work?</p></li>
</ol>
<h2 id='p-2'>Lucky</h2>
<p>Us, I mean; lucky to be alive just now, watching these big games play
out.  Billions of dollars are at stake but that’s a sideshow. We’re working
out ways for the people of the future to talk with each other.  There are
lots of possible outcomes; the ones that seem likely to me
look mostly pretty decent.</p>
</div></content></entry>

</feed>
